the interests of any citizen are to eat well and
интересы любого гражданина это сытно
drink sweetly and you and we have it
жрать сладко пить и у вас и у нас
right and accordingly the country
правильно и соответственно страна
chooses the way to provide the
выбирает способ как обеспечить
citizen with a hearty meal Understand Elementary Oh,
гражданину сытно жратву Поня Элементарно
such an interesting question Do you go to the elections
О интересный такой вопрос Вы на выборы
No, I don't go
ходите Нет не хожу
Yeah That is, I understand that you
Ага То есть я понял вы в своей стране
yourself do nothing in your country  decide but Tell me
сами ничего не решаете но Рассказывайте
about some geopolitics And so on
про какую-то геополитику И так дальше
Hello Hello I am from the city of
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsky Where are you from I am from the
Хмельницкий Вы откуда Я из
city blogger Yes blogger now
города блогер Да блогер сечас
ri
ри
understandably a lot watches you now just
понятно много смотрит вас сечас только
started now charged now we
начали сечас зарядились то сечас
are watching What is the purpose of these streams With what
смотрим Какая задача эти стримов С какой
several Yes watch
ль несколько Да смотрите
the main  some side effects For example,
основные некоторые побочные Вот например
one of the main goals is to influence the
Одна из основных целей - это влияние
Russian audience, a lot of
на российскую аудиторию меня очень много
people from Russia watch me, including
смотрит людей из России в том числе
many who write to me, some do good
пишут мне многи некоторые делают хорошие
things, for example, military registration and enlistment offices contact
вещи там военкоматы например связываются
our special services, some write
с нашими спецслужбами некоторые пишут
simply that they understood, for example,
просто что там понял например ваши
I watched your streams, I understood, for example  such things
стримы смотрел понял например такие вещи
second
второе
we collect donations during streams on the
собираем донаты во время стримов на
armed forces of Ukraine bringing the pillow closer
вооруженные силы Украины приближая поду
third We raise the spirits of Ukrainians and  To
третье Поднимаем настроение украинцам и
all the Good people who support
всем Хорошим людям которые поддерживают
Ukraine, that is, morally in these difficult
Украину то есть морально в эти сложные
times, yes, we
времена да ээ
understand
понимаем
the mood. Well, I
настроение Ну понятно
understand. That is, your task is not to find out
понятно То есть у вас задача не узнать
some truth. Yes, there about Russia. And the
какую-то правду Да там про Россию А
task is to achieve some kind of superiority.
задача добиться какого-то превосходства
Logs are correct. Well, look, my task is not to
логи правильно Ну смотрите моя задача не
find out.  some truth Yes, and to impose
узнать какую-то правду Да а навязать
your truth because the truth It is behind
свою правду потому что правда Она за
us The
нами
truth is behind us yes that is if I
Правда она за нами да то есть если я
understand well if I think that it is
понимаю ну если я считаю что это
right Yes, of course I want to convey these things
правильно Да я конечно хочу эти вещи
to a wide circle of people If there is
донести до широкого круга лиц Если есть
a person who wants to challenge my
человек который хочет оспорить мою
truth I can always debate with him
правду Я всегда могу с ним
Yes but unfortunately
подискутировать Да но к сожалению
most Russians can't are not capable
большинство россиян не могут не способны
of constructive dialogue at least
на конструктивный диалог по крайней мере
those who are in
те которые в
chatroulette Well I will say that the years of pain of
чатрулетке Ну я скажу что лет боль
Ukrainians are also not a way Nan
украинцев тоже не способ Нан постольку
since apparently chatroulette is not the
поскольку видимо чато рулетка не тот
resource that attracts mainly
ресурс который привлекает в основном
wise public yes that is my opinion that it is
мудрую публику да то есть моё мнение что
estimated that here Levin's
оценочно такое что здесь всё-таки Левина
share is still Well so People on both sides are like that Well
доля Ну так Народ с обой сторон тако Ну
ordinary people Yes ordinary voters
обычный народ Да обычные избиратели
of which the bulk are Well well I think that
которых основная масса Да ну я думаю что
still below average in intelligence
всё-таки ниже среднего по интеллекту
maybe even below average so  from both
может даже ниже среднего так с обоих
sides That's because people who are more
сторон Вот потому что люди более
intelligent are less likely to conceive roulette Well, someone
интеллектуальные реже зачат рулетку Ну
like me probably rarely conceives
такой как я наверное на редкости вчать
roulette Well, it's just that people usually don't sit in
рулетке Ну просто это обычно не сидят в
chatroulette yes, yes, well, someone smokes, someone
чатрулетке да да ну кто-то курит кто-то
drinks too, when I go out into the networks in the pen,
бухает тоже когда в ручке выхожу в сетки
like there's a deputy on a shirt right away  they say
типа там рубашке депутат сразу говорят
Yes, I have a bad habit of chatting,
Да вот у меня вредна привычка пообщаться
arguing, discussing, for example, this is a
поспорить подискутировать например это
bad habit of mine, what should I do?
вредно привычка моя что делать сда много
I spend a lot of time fighting this, I try to
времени я с этим борюсь стараюсь
fight it, but nevertheless, I just drive
бороться но тем не менее просто диску
for the sake of discussion.
ради дискуссии
Yes, I like the
Да мне нравится
general Ravi general in
обща Рави обща в
once upon a time there was a popular video, another
когда-то популяр там один ролик другой
video  how do they communicate with the disk and understand that
ролик как диску общаются и понима что
most of them call bloggers and
большинство называем блогеров и
participants of the disk completely without knowing
участников ча диску совершенно не зная
the subject of the discussion many start just to
предмета дискуссию многи начинают лишь
get out of it in short and you
бы короче выкручиваться а вы
by the way just sensibly that chu which they
кстати просто дельно ту чу которой они
actually say
говорят на самом
lyut koda lyut nonsense I go VP and argue Yes it's
лют кода лю чушь Я иду ВП и спорю Да это
bad  better not do it and I in this SPO
плохо лучше не делайте это а я этом СПО
so nicely thinking person here I
так приятно мыслящего человека сразу вот
will ask a thinking person a question That's
мыслящего человеку задам вопрос Вот
why Russia  attacked Ukraine
почему Россия напала на Украину
in your opinion as a thinking person well my
по-вашему как мыслящий человек ну моя
my personal opinion the task
моё личное мнение задача
was to change the political power in your
была сменить политическую власть в вашей
country to more proya about Russian
стране на более на проя про российскую
my personal opinion Well and in the end nothing
моё личное мнение Ну и в итоге ничего не
worked out and got into a real war And
получилось и вляпались настоящею войну А
you support the ideas here to change these there
вы поддержите идеи вот эти там поменять
power in
власть в
Ukraine Well let's say it like this uh war is
Украине Ну давайте говорить так э война
bad not of course Yes but there is
- это плохо не безусловно Да но есть
another point there is Geopolitics uh which
другой момент есть Геополитика э которая
uh in which there are interests of different countries
э в которой есть интересы у разных стран
yes the small ones have small interests the
да у маленьких маленькие интересы
big ones have big interests Yes and Russia
больших большие интересы Да и У России
has its own geopolitical interests If we
есть свои геополитические интересы Если
talk about  geopolitics yes from a
говорить о геополитике да с
geopolitical point of view not from a
геополитической точки зрения не с
moral point of view yes from a
моральной там да именно с
geopolitical point of view Russia should leave
геополитической э Россия должна оставить
its rights how does this turn out with the program
свои права как это получается прогой
look, do I understand correctly that
смотрите вот я так правильно понимаю что
you support Russia's actions yes in
вы поддерживаете действия России да по
attacking Ukraine to establish
нападению на Украину для установления
some kind of regime there Well then  I
своего какого-то там режима Так ну я
would say probably it should have been done
сказал бы наверное надо было делать
somehow differently probably like this
как-то по-другому наверно как вот
Let's do it So you will support yours or not
Давайте Так вы поддержите сво или не
Well let's start with ma yes
поддержите Ну давайте начнём с ма да
If a country has already decided to enter the
Если уж страна решила заходить на
territory of another country yes yes  military
территорию другой страны да да воен
military forces then at least this should be done
военной Сил то хотя бы это надо делать
according to the regulations
по уста
I'm not asking Look I'm not asking according to the
Я не спрашиваю Смотри я не спрашиваю по
regulations Do you support the solution of the
уставу Вы поддерживаете решение
Ukrainian issue by force on
украинского вопроса силовым методом со
the part of Russia yes or no you as a
стороны России да или нет вы как
thinking person well I didn't meet some kind of
мыслящий человек вот я же не какой-то
cattle but a thinking person
[__] встретил а вот мыслящего человека
finally I think that there probably
наконец-то Я считаю что наверное другого
was no other way Yeah, there was no That is, you
пути уже не было Ага не было То есть вы
as a thinking person say How do
как мыслящий человек Говорите Как вот
I like all this from
мне всё
some state bu this is Russia bu the
какого-то государства бу это Россия бу
USA bu This is France bu This is Great Britain
США бу Это Франция бу Это Великобритания
if we speak from this position a  not
если говорить именно с этой позиции а не
from a
с позиции
moral standpoint I'm asking you now not as a
морали Я вас спрашиваю сейчас не как
statesman but as a
государственно мужа а как
citizen I as a citizen say that
гражданина Я как гражданин говорю что
Russia has the right to take its own date
Россия имеет право зать сво ли дате вас
your interests as a citizen coincide with the
ваши интересы как гражданина совпадают с
fact that it is necessary to attack
тем что надо напасть на
Ukraine saying yes because Gru
Украину говоря да потому Гру говоря
roughly speaking the interests of anyone  citizen
грубо говоря интерес любого гражданина
it is satisfying to eat sweet to drink and you and
это сытно жрать сладко пить и вас и у
we have the government and accordingly the country
нас прави и соответственно страна
chooses the way to provide the
выбирает способ как обеспечить
citizen with a
гражданину сыт
satisfying meal such an interesting question Do you go to the
жратву интересный такой вопрос Вы на
elections
выборы
No I don't go that is I understand you are
ходите Нет не хожу а то есть я понял вы
in your country  you don't decide anything yourself
в своей стране сами ничего не
but
решаете но
is that right? I understand personally I am
ли так да правильно Поня меня лично меня
satisfied with the way the economy is developing.
устраивает Как развивается именно
I understood correctly that as a
экономика Я правильно понял вы как
thinking person you allow this cattle
мыслящий человек позволяете быдлу этому
who sits there eating and drinking to go
который сидит жрёт там бухает ходить за
to the elections for you. And I personally am satisfied with the
вас на выборы А меня лично устраивает
way the economy of my country is developing. I am just
как ыва экономика моей страны Я просто
asking.  look I'm not asking whether
спрашиваю смотрите я же не спрашиваю или
you are satisfied with the economy I'm asking
вас устраивает экономика Я вас спрашиваю
you as a thinking
вы как мыслящий
person you are giving the cattle the right to
человек отдаёте быдлу нес право без
walk without a cattle and cattle walk and not cattle I think
ходит и [__] ходит и не [__] Я считаю
that personally nothing depends on my vote there
что лично от моего голоса там уже ничего
nothing that is you I understand
не зависит ничего не то есть вы я понял
you as a thinking person  man you say
вы как мыслящий человек говорите
how did it happen that
что как так получилось что от вашего
nothing depends on your vote Well because
голоса ничего не зависит Ну потому что
probably we don't have an ideal democracy I
наверное у нас не идеальная демократия Я
assume that is to say that your
предполагаю а то есть у вас
elections are falsified you
фальсифицируют выборы вы это имеете в
mean no we don't have falsified elections
виду нет у нас не фальсифицируют выборы
How do you understand we don't have an ideal
Как понять у нас не идеальная
democracy Well  as in the whole world There is no
демократия Ну как во всём мире Нет
ideal democracy Everywhere there are
идеальной демократии Везде есть свои
nuances of democracy once again Who
нюансы демократии ещё раз Кто у вас
elects your deputies and
избирает депутатов и
presidents The people the people are
президентов Народ народ это есть
democrats the people Israel
демократи народ Изра
demo is another matter  who is allowed as a
демо другое дело кого допускают в
candidate then the problem is that you have someone
кандидаты то проблема что у вас кто-то
usurping
узурпировать
those whom the people want
тех кого хочет народ
so Perhaps Perhaps yes Yeah I got it that is
так Возможно Возможно да Ага понял то
all that is it turns out you have
есть всё то есть получается у вас есть
some kind of political elite that
какая-то политическая верхушка которая
has closed itself off and does not allow outsiders there
закрылась и не допускает туда сторонних
Perhaps yes I got it interesting  yes,
людей Возможно да понял интересно да то
that is, it turns out that this political
есть получается эта политическая
elite has deprived you and other citizens of
верхушка лишила вас и других граждан так
political power in the country,
политической власти в стране
perhaps, perhaps, so the question is in
возможно возможно так вопрос в интересах
whose interests this political elite is acting,
кого действует эта политическая верхушка
in the interests of itself, the political elite,
в интересах себя политической верхушки
or in the interests of the
или в интересах
people Well, I'll tell you in response, I'll
народа Ну вот я вам скажу в ответе я
tell you now, I'll ask something  question and
сейчас скажу кое что задам вопрос и в
answer if in my city let's say yes in
ответе если в моём городе допустим да за
15-10 years they built 25 kindergartens for example In
лет 15-10 построили 25 садиков например
whose interests was this done for example
Это ких интересах было сделано например
Or maybe or maybe they could have built 25
А может а может могли построить 25
look In the front don't interrupt me
смотри Во пере не не перебивайте меня
when I interrupt I'll look again You
когда перебиваю я ещё раз смотрите Вы
said they built 15 kindergartens  Or maybe or
сказали построили 15 садиков А может а
maybe
может
they built Or maybe 50 kindergartens could have been
построили А может 50 садиков могли
built but only 15 were built Yes
построить а построили только 15 да
The question is not that, the question now is
Вопрос не в том во вопрос сейчас в том
that some people Yes limited your
что какие-то люди Да ограничили ваше
voting rights  all questions will be
избирательное права все лю вопросы буде
asked only by you we will stop
задавать только вы мы прекратим
the discussion Don't look I asked you I
дискуссию Не смотрите я вам задал я
understood You fried on the question of elections
понял Вы поджарили на вопро выборов
Yes I asked you I asked you you asked a question
Да я вам я вам вы задали вопрос по
about the elections I answer you what in the
поводу выборов я вам отвечаю че чех
interests of 15 kindergartens you asked Yes in the
интересах 15 садиков вы спросили Да
interests of kindergartens build Tell me 15
интерес садики построе Скажите 15
kindergartens  built in
садиков построены в
the interests of 25 yes 25 kindergartens were built
интересах 25 да 25 садики построены
partly in the interests of the people and partly in the
частично в интересах народа а частично в
interests of the ruling elite because they
интересах правляча элиты потому что
could have built 50 kindergartens I explain because they
могли построить 50 Сади объясняю потому
could have built 50 kindergartens the money for
что могли построить 50 садиков деньги на
25 kindergartens was stolen and 25 would have
25 садиков украли а 25 для отмазки бы
been made as an excuse Yes it is
сделали Да
clear what you will do don't wait
понятно что вы сделаете не подожди
now  question e time
теперь вопрос е раз
question I don't want I accepted your answer
вопрос я не хочу я принял ваш ответ
Now look The question is
Теперь смотрите Вопрос такой получается
that you as a person don't decide anything in
что вы как человек ничего не решаете в
your country you just like how everything
своей стране вам просто нравится как всё
is happening correctly I like how
происходит правильно Мне нравится как
the economy is developing earlier
развивается экономика ране
[music]
[музыка]
mche doesn't decide anything correctly I heard you
мче ничего не решает правильно я вас
m people are satisfied How the
м народ устраивает Как развивается
economy is developing I didn't ask or are satisfied I
экономика Я не спросил или устраивает Я
asked whether the people decide something or not
спросил решает ли что-то народ или не
Why are you  you ask such
решает А зачем вы задаёте такие вопросы
provocative questions you specifically want because
провокационные Вы специально хоти потому
I am a provocateur I went provocative questions
я провокатор я шл провокационный вопросы
but you are the provocateurs you don't
а вот как раз таки вы провокаторы вы не
want I provocateur No I am asking you a difficult
хотите я прово Нет я вам задаю сложный
question for you and you call it
для вас вопрос А вы его называете
provocative What city are you in what
провокационный В каком городе Вы в каком
city Let's not ask the question  run away you
городе Давайте за вопро не убегайте вы
want to run away see I'm you are a horse
хотите убежать видите я вас кон
we are talking Nara I asked you a question
мы общаемся Нара я вам задал вопрос
look you are
смотрите Вы
running away citizens of Russia something I
убегаем граждане России что-то я Вам
repeat the question to you five times citizens of Russia
пять раз повторяю вопрос граждане России
decide something in this country or are you just
что-то решают в этой стране или просто
not a journalist you are not a journalist I am not a
не журналист вы не журналист я не
politician just  I'm asking you once, do
политик чтобы только е раз вам спрашиваю
citizens of Russia decide something yes or no
граждане России что-то решают да или нет
Just
Просто
let's agree Say yes
давайте согласен Скажите да
and I agree, do citizens of Russia decide something in
и согласен граждане России что-то решают
this country yes or no I don't know I do
этой стране да или нет не знаю не знаю
n't know I understand well that is, it doesn't decide
не знаете понял хорошо то есть не решает
Let's have my question my question is in yours  in
Давай мой вопрос мой вопрос в вашем
the city how many kindergartens were built in 20
городе сколько садиков построили за 20
years in 20 years I don't know the same exact
лет за 20 лет не знаю тоже точно такой
question why not enough Why are you answering for me
вопрос почему мало не Почему вы за меня
you asked me a question I
отвечаете вы задали мне вопрос я вам
asked you an answer now I'm asking you a question
задал ответ теперь я вам задаю вопрос
No we agreed  question question now
Нет мы договорились вопрос вопрос теперь
I
я вам
ask you What are the people called who decide
задаю Как называются люди которые в
absolutely nothing in their country do
своей стране абсолютно ничего не
you think you are on And do you think
решают вы думаете вас на А вы думаете
Ukrainians decide everything I you ask me
украинцы всё решают я вы меня спросите
you ask me Answer my question
вы меня спросите Ответьте на мой вопрос
and then ask me I asked you a question
а потом меня спросите я вам задал вопрос
what are the people called who do not  I know how which
как называются люди не знаю как которые
I don't know what to call people who do
я не знаю как называть э людей которые
n't decide anything for their country Well,
ничего не решают своей стране Ну версию
offer your version Not me you just have
вашу предложите Не я у вас просто мне
your interesting version if
ваша интересная версия если
not I don't know How to call I don't know How to
нет я не знаю Как обозвать Я не знаю Как
call You have a version not I don't know You
обозвать У вас есть версия не не знаю Вы
Ask  I have my own question now
Задайте мне теперь свой вопрос давай
okay okay Ukrainians decide
хорошо хорошо украинцы решает свой
something in their country
стране что-нибудь
yes How is it now my question don't
да Каким образом сейчас мой вопрос не
rush see you don't know
спешите видите у вас не зна
Yes my question is
Да мой вопрос
so people who in their country
так люди которые в своей стране Ничего
absolutely don't decide anything are
абсолютно не решают являются
slaves No okay your question those are my question
рабами Нет окей ваш вопро те мой вопрос
now  my
теперь мой
question as a result of the changes of six or there n
вопрос в результате смен шести или там н
something has changed in the right direction in Ukraine
что-то изменилось в лу сторону Украине
yes exactly
да именно
with the question people who do not decide anything in
с вопрос люди которые ничего не решают в
their country can be called
своей стране могут назваться
serfs no understood
крепостными нет понял
let's about Let's have our question
давайте про Давайте свой вопрос
[music] let's
[музыка]
say adj Poroshenko What has changed in the
допустим прил Порошенко Что изменилось
right direction quality
лую сторону качество
life How is this next  question
жизни Каким образом это следущий вопрос
sii
сй
zhda question If in Russia yes the ruling
жда вопрос Если в России да правящая
elite will pass some law with a
верхушка примет закон какой-то с
cat glasno this will not
котом гласно вот их не будет это
suit them for example mobilization yes or
устраивать например мобилизация да Или
something else Yes Eh how can people influence
ещё что-то Да Ээ как люди могут повлиять
this ruling elite
на эту правящую верхушку
eh most people were not upset with
э большинство людей не расстроились с
this mobilization  I didn't ask or
этой мобилизации Я не спросил или
were upset I asked the question I'll repeat the
расстроились Я задал вопрос повторю
question how will people influence the
вопрос как люди повлияют на решение
government's decision that doesn't
правительства которое их не
suit them eh when was the last time the people in
устраивает э когда последний раз народ в
Russia definitely didn't suit anything with taught with
России точно ничего не устроил с учил с
Bolotnaya square If you don't
Болотной площадь Если вы не
remember most people something I didn't
помните большинство людей чтото я не
ask what happened look answer
спросил что случи смотрите ответьте
directly to the question that something will happen to people
прямо на вопрос что людей что-то будет
if the majority of people are
если большинство людей что-то будет
very satisfied with something they will come out so I
сильно устраивать они выйдут так всё
heard your
услышал ваш
question That's when I asked the question what
вопрос Вот когда я задал вопрос что им
has changed for them you didn't want to answer I
изменилось вы не захотели отвечать Я
think that when a person knows that something
считаю что когда человек знает что
has changed for the better he has something to do
изменилось лучшую сторону ему есть чем
poh Tell me the
пох Скажите
question What exactly has changed in any
вопрос Что именно изменилось в лую
direction in terms of the standard of living Yes, we are
сторону плане уровень жизни Да у нас
building new schools
строят новые школы
And that's all I give you an example of the answer the standard of
А всё я вам пример ска ответ уровень
living has increased and further if you want to clarify,
жизни увел и всё дальше хотите уточнить
ask the following question Can you
зададите Следующий вопрос Можно можно
clarify the following No, no, this is the next
уточнить следу Нет нет это Следующий
question will be No  don't rush you
вопрос будет Нет не спешите это же
see we are playing I can
видите мы играем Я же тоже умею в такой
play basketball like that too yes you see right ro for the sake of the
баскетбол играть да Видите пра ро ради
question who are you in your country
вопрос кто вы в своей стране
And I am a citizen if if we talk from this
А я гражданин если если говорить с это
point of view here is from the point of view of the
точки зрения вот е с точки зрения
social
социальной
level I am an
ступеньки Я
entrepreneur Let's ask our
предприниматель Давайте свой
question how have you changed  income of Ukrainians
вопрос как изменились доходы украинцев
after Poroshenko came to power income of
после прихода к власти Порошенко доходы
Ukrainians after Poroshenko came to power
украинцев после прихода к власти
grew grew Yes I answered wait
выросли выросли Да я ответил подождите я
I answered I answered the question but income
ответил Я ответил вопрос но доходы
grew my income grew
выросли мой доход вырос
bull
быка
besides that's all my next now
притом выс всё следующий мой тепер
question come in and this is your next
вопрос заходите и сй это ваш следующий
will be Question next question So  now
будет Вопрос следущий вопрос Так теперь
a question for you And what rights does a
к вам вопрос А какие права есть у
citizen have? As a citizen, what
гражданина у вас как у гражданина Какие
rights do you
права
have? Civil
есть гражданские
liberties, for example,
Свободы например
Medin, free medical care, free
Медин бесплат медицинская бесплатная
assistance, what
помощ что
[music],
[музыка]
also security, the right to
ещё безопасность право на
security, what else, and so on and
безопасность что ещё ну и так далее так
so forth, I can't remember right away.
далее так далее сразу не вспомнишь
Let's have yours  question see You don't tell me
Давайте ваш вопрос видите Вы не мне пови
that you didn't remember the basic rights of a
что вы не вспомнили основные права
citizen Let's yes If we
гражданина Давайте да Если мы будем
play with the wording Let's if we
играть в формулировки Давайте если мы
pick on the
будем с вами придираться к
wording I'll ask you any question
формулировками я вам задам любой вопрос
that you don't answer right away we won't do
на который сразу не ответите мы не будем
that  give before I was just interested
так давать пре мне просто было интересно
here or you voice All I
вот или вы озвучить Всё я же ничего не
have nothing wai question ok
имею вай вопрос хорошо
And by how many percent did the income of
А на сколько процентов выросли доходы
Ukrainians increase with the coming to power of Poroshenko
украинцев с приходом к власти Порошенко
and How did your inflation change how Did
и Как изменилась у вас инфляция как
prices increase after the coming to power of Vasya
Выросли цены после прихода К Васе
Poroshenko and is the growth related
Порошенко при этом соотносится ли рост
salaries with rising prices with rising
зарплаты с ростом цен с ростом расходов
living expenses yes, that's a very good question, so
на жизнь да очень хороший вопрос значит
look, in every country there is
смотрите в каждой стране происходит
inflation, including in Russia after
инфляция в том числе и в России после
Poroshenko came to power after any
прихода Порошенко после прихода любого
president came to power Yes, inflation is happening because it is happening
президента Да инфляция идёт потому что
regardless of the president if
она идёт независимо от президента если
we look at inflation, for example, how did it
мы посмотрим например инфляция Как
go  from the beginning of Putin's presidency and
прошла от начала президентства Путина и
now yes you'll be shocked how much
сейчас да Вы офигеете да насколько
inflation has gone Yes it just hasn't changed for you
прошла инфляция Да просто у вас он не
now the second question is Ukraine Yes
менялся теперь второй вопрос Украина Да
in economic indicators it was even
по экономическим показателям даже многим
ahead of Russia in many ways Despite the fact that we
опережал Россию Несмотря на то что у нас
had a Russian invasion in 2014 yes
было российское вторжение в 2014 году да
as of January 1, 2022  so before the
на 1 января 2022 года так до
full-scale invasion Ukraine reached the
полномасштабного вторжения Украина вышла
minimum wage level indicators
на показатели минимального уровня оплаты
higher than in Russia I can
труда выше чем в России это я могу
open this now and read out the numbers directly Yes
сейчас открыть и прямо зачитать числа Да
Despite the fact that Russia in  2014
Несмотря на то что Россия в 2014 напала
attacked our economy collapsed because of the
у нас обрушилась экономика из-за
attack because we have a war we
нападения из-за того что у нас война мы
were able to achieve in a country at war
смогли в воюющей стране добиться того
that we have a minimum
что у нас минимальный уровень зарплаты
wage you as entrepreneurs should
труда вы как предприниматели это должны
understand this Yes we had it on January 1,
понимать Да у нас он был на 1 января
to announce yes  you had what let's say
года озвучить да у вас было что давайте
you had like 83 dollars we have
у вас было вроде 83 доллара у нас с
something
чем-то
like that you are talking about gender or about
такро вы говорите про род или про
salary the size of the salary I what are you you an
зарплату размер оплаты труда я вы что вы
entrepreneur I didn't say the word
предприниматель Я не сказал слово
average salary I said here you have on
средняя зарплата Я же сказа вот у вас на
January 1 look at  On January 1st the minimum wage
1 января смотрите на 1 января МРОТ ф
was
составлял
13,890 rubles, I'm right, yes, yes, approximately so,
13890 руб я прав да да примерно
what was the dollar exchange rate, so the rate was
так какой курс доллара был так курс
approximately 60, I'll definitely look, I'm
примерно примерно 60 я точно посмотрю я
definitely a mathematician, I'm looking very subtly,
точно я математик я так тоненько смотрю
so here are the exchange
так вот валютных
rates
курсов
of the Central Bank, so on January 1st the rate was two, no-no,
Центробанк так 1 января курс два не-не
no, stop, stop, stop  this is
не стоп стоп стоп это
Ukrainian there is
украинский есть
so the rate for the
так курс на
first was se no no 70 about 75
первого был се не не 70 порядка 75
was about 75 75 So let's look That
был порядка 75 75 Так давайте смотрим То
is you had it
есть у вас это
90 de on
90 де на
75 1
75 1
here  184 to
вот 184 до
184 dollars in Russia was the minimum
184 доллара в России был минимальный
wage we open Ukraine
размер оплаты труда открываем Украину
minimum
минимальный
wage
розмер
Zarubina
Зарубиной
02 here from January 1, 2022 22 the
02 вот с 1 сичня 2022 22 года
minimum wage was
минимальный размер заработной платы был
set at 6,500 hryvnia Yes we look at the dollar exchange rate
установлен в 6.500 гривн Да смотрим курс
Well, about the same as the
доллара Ну примерно та же в итоге как
ruble sweat is not the same  one and a half times
рубля пот не та же в полтора раза будет
more no one and a half times more
больше нет в полтора раза будет больше
or 30-40 more so we had a dollar
или на 30-40 больше так у нас был доллар
2728 look 2728 and now the numbers are
2728 смотрите 2728 и сечас цифр так
6,500 Green divided by 27 dollars 28
6.500 Грин делим на 27 долларов 28
cents and we get 238 dollars That is in
центов и получаем 238 долларов То есть в
Ukraine the minimum size was 238 dollars
Украине был 238 долларов минимальный
wages in Russia 184 divide
размер оплаты труда в России 184 делим
100 wait divide 200 wait divide 238
100 подожди делим 200 подожди делим 238
by 4 and we get that in Ukraine it was 30%
на4 и получаем что в Украине на 30% было
more now Next question What
больше теперь Следующий вопрос Какой
percentage of Russians live on the minimum and
процент россиян живут на минималку и
What percentage of Ukraine's minimum
Какой процент Укра минима ещё раз
look at the minimum again Not the minimum we are
смотрите минималку Не минималку мы
now You  agree This is an
сейчас Вы согласны Вот это есть
economic indicator This is not an
экономический показатель Это не
economic indicator economic
экономический показатель экономический
indicator
показатель
avg once again once again there is an average there is
сре ещё раз ещё раз есть средняя есть
a median There are different let's do this
медианная Есть разные давайте так
minimum wage
минимальный размер оплаты труда
economic
экономический
indicator No it is not set from the head
показатель Нет он же не из головы
it is not an economic
устанавливается он не экономический
indicator economic indicator
показатель экономический показатель
What is this indicator What is this indicator
Какой это показа Какой это показатель
physical chemical what is
физический химический какой в России
this indicator in Russia do you know for is it used
этот показатель знаете для применяется
for
для
issuance I will say that we have entrepreneurs
вып скажу у нас у предпринимателей
minimum to labor is used only
минимальна к труда применяется только
for calculating the minimum official
для начисления минимальной официальной
salary of the Armed Forces the
зарплаты ВС
rest we can not
остальное не можем
Less rubles
Мень руб
we can pay a salary of 50,000 rubles yes
мы можем платить оклад 50.000 руб да
we can 100 but many entrepreneurs
можем 100 но многие предприниматели
officially pay only 14 CH  on this
платят официально только 14 ЧР на это
first second this is all in short this is smo
первое второе это всё короче это смо ещ
again let's go further further What percentage of
раз давай дальше дальше Какой процент
Russians live on the Minimum once again do you
россиян живёт на Минимал ещё раз у вас
have you have data if there is we
есть у вас есть данные если есть мы
can talk about them If we can we
сможем про них поговорить Если можем мы
compare I don't know who I don't know
сравнить я не знаю кто я не знаю Видите
See look  that's it that's it And I don't know
вот смотри вот Вот именно И я не знаю у
I don't have this data Yes I can I know about the
меня нету данных этих Да я могу я знаю с
salary in Russia I can discuss
зарплату в Росси я могу с вами обсуждать
specific indicators with you here I take the
конкретные показатели вот я беру
minimum wage this is a
минимальный размер оплаты труда это
clear indicator
чёткий показатель который
that in your opinion  if in your opinion if in
вот по вашему если по вашему если по
your opinion then tell me how much
вашему тогда скажите сколько
it is Let's do it Let's
идт Давай мы точ Давай мы точку в этом
do it Let's do it that pos Otta on utility
поставим той пос Отта на коммунальные
costs once again let's do it
расходы ещё раз давай мы ставим насчёт
that is a person in
этого точку то есть человек так в
Ukraine working for a minimum
Украине работающий на минимальную
wage received received before the
зарплату получа получа до вторжения
Russian invasion than a person  in Russia working
России чем человек в России работающий
for a minimum wage if the minimum
на минимальную зарплату если минималке
then like yes And if real salary Wait I'm not
то типа да А если реам зарп Подожди я не
saying if not if here's the
говорю если не если вот
situation with you Do you have people
чело ситуация у вас У вас есть люди
who work less than the minimum
которые работают меньше минимальной
wage
зарплаты
I don't know such people not because there is no The
получают Я таких не знаю не потому что
thing is that there is no  maybe in Moscow in
Дело в том что нет може в Москве в
Moscow maybe you won't survive But in the Urals
Москве может не выживете А на Урале
maybe you will survive or in some village Yes in the
может выживете или в селе каком-то Да на
Urals What are you saying my mother is a
Урале Что вы говорите вот у меня мама
pensioner she gets a pension of 22,000
пенсионерка она получает пенсию 22.000
rubles for example how much is that 200
руб например это сколько это 200
dollars you know at the same time
долларов вы знаете при этом коммуналку
she pays 23,000 for utilities  200 dollars how much is
она платит 23000 з 200 долларов сколько
this a small pension this is a small
это маленькая пенсия это маленькая
pension only your pensioners this
пенсия только только ваши пенсионеры это
200 dollars I'm asking this is 200
200 долларов я спрашиваю это 200
dollars Now stop stop you now stop stop
долларов Сейчас стоп стоп ты сейчас стоп
stop you now no you now don't
стоп стоп ты сейчас нет ты сейчас не
run away You just bragged about your
убегай Ты сейчас похвастался пенсией у
mom's pension of 200 dollars I'm not running how much work experience does
мамы в 200 дол Я не бегаю сколько стажа
TMA have I don't know I don't know How much work experience does your mom have
у Т МА Сколько у твоей мамы стажа не
No you  entrepreneur you are an
знаю Нет ты предприниматель ты
entrepreneur Look you No I am not
предприниматель Смотри ты Нет я тебя не
listening to you everything look Wait I
слуша всё смотри Подожди я тебя
am asking you You tell me what you bragged
спрашиваю Ты скажи что ты похвастался
bragged tell me I am bragging that I
похвастался скажи я хвастаюсь тем что
owe that my mother I am not bragging that my
дол что мое ма я не хвастаюсь что моей
mother's pension is only 200 dollars You don't
ма пенсия всего 200 долларов Ты же не
want me to listen to you
хочешь меня послу ты
What  nssi ukrai today te s ne
хо Какая нси украи сегодня те с не
look you now
смотри ты сейчас мне
answer me in Ukrainian And
ответь украински И
Russia wait you said that
Росси подожди ты говорил что на
no one will survive on the minimum wage with
минимальную зарплату никто не выживет у
you yes of
вас да
course You now have your minimum wage
коне У вас сейчас сейчас у вас МРОТ
how much
сколько
approximately 14,000 rubles How where approximately
примерно 14.000 руб Как где примерно у
you have a birth I don't know I don't know  Well, you have it
вас ро род не знаю не знаю Ну у вас вот
since January 1st already  16,000 200 was that is
с с 1 января Уже 16.000 200 было то есть
look Your mother now here and now
смотри Твоя мама сейчас вот а сейчас вот
from January 1, 2024 that is now there will be
с 1 января 2024 то есть вот сейчас будет
19,000 rubles That is it turns out Your
тея 19.000 руб То есть получается Твоя
mother now also receives a pension in
мама сейчас получает тоже само пенсию на
Russia and in Ukraine by right wait
России и на Украине по правильно подожди
right look The fact is that the pension
правильно смотри Дело в том что пенсия у
each person has a different Truth is true yes
каждого человека разная Правда правда да
we can't compare we need to compare the
мы не можем сравнить надо сравнивать
average pension And you and I don't have it and the
среднюю пенсию А мы с тобой её не и
average pension What is it in Ukraine and we don't
средняя пенсия Какая на Украине а мы не
know And how to look at the average where is
знаем А как посмотреть среднюю где у
your average pension you don't know ka pe
тебя средняя пенси ты не знаешь ка пе
Ukraine I don't know that's me  I see for example
Укра не знаю вот я я вижу например
specifically Let me open the cards Let me
конкретно Давай я открою карты Давай те
open the cards we have relatives in
открою карты у нас есть родственники в
Khmelnitsky I am from the city of Khmelnitsky
Хмельницком мне я города Хмельницкий
Look I have different people in Khmelnitsky
Смотри у меня есть в Хмельницком разные
Yes, that's it, you can find out
люди Да вот вот вот можете узнать
how much pensions people receive pensions in
сколько получают пенсии пенси
Khmelnitsky [ __ ] you agree that in one
Хмельницком сри ты согласен что в одном
city people receive  different pensions
городе люди получают разную пенсию в
depending on how they work,
зависимости от того что как они рабо си
it doesn't differ much, but once again,
она не сильно отличается по го ещё раз у
people in the same city have different pensions  pension is
людей в одном городе отличается пенсия
a little different everything Therefore we
немножко отли отличается всё Поэтому мы
can't Yes we can't compare
не можем Да мы не можем сравнивать
for example I have a friend with meniscus
например вот у меня в мениском знакомый
yes he gets 1,000 dollars in pension
да он получает 1.000 долларов пенсии
for example And what does this say it doesn't
например И что это говорит это ничего не
say anything really Yes it doesn't say anything
говорит правда Да это ничего не гот
Therefore s a om genus Look you wait  you
Поэтому с а ом род Смотри ты подожди ты
just admitted you admitted that your
только что признал ты признал что твоё
government pays your mother a
государство выплачивает твоей маме
pension on which It is impossible to survive you
пенсию на который Невозможно выжить ты
said it is impossible to survive on the minimum wage wait on
говорил на МРОТ нельзя выжить подожди по
Wait wait I have no ambassador
Подожди подожди Яя у ва послу
attentively
внимательно
that's right wait you just told me
нета правильно подожди ты мне только что
you just admitted that your mother
ты только что признал что твоя мама
lives Beyond the brink of survival  your
живёт За гранью выживания твоя
state where don't run
государство куда не убегай
now Nida run away mouth I am
сечас Нида убегай р тво я
now look your mother your mother lives
сечас смотри твоя мама твоя мама живёт
on the edge of survival lu you said with your
на грани выживания лу ты сказал своим
mouth that no one can survive on the minimum wage
ртом что на МРОТ у вас никто выжить не
you don't have mro
может мро у вас
now don't confuse the minimum wage
сечас нета не путай минимальную зарплату
with the minimum subsistence minimum they are
с минимальным прожиточным минимумом это
different  things minimum wage not you and
разные вещи минимальная зарплата не мы с
I about the minimum wage we didn't talk about the minimum wage at all
тобой о прожиточном минимум вообще не
you and I  talked only about the
говорили мы с тобой говорили только о
minimum wage for
минимальном размере платы
other workers We don't talk
трудам другом Мы не говори ещ три мы ни
about the World Cup yet You said that no one You have
о ЧМ другом ты сказал что никто У вас у
people who get less than the minimum
вас люди получают меньше минимально
wage
зарплаты
now jump off [ __ ] now
сейчас соскочить бля сейчас
jump off put a plus who was
соскочить поставьте плюс кому
honored with your roast I just
сподобалась тя прожарка я просто
enjoyed Yak Vin and zvervatsya
кайфовал Як вин и звертався
yes  Poroshenko, not Poroshenko, there you
да Порошенко не Порошенко там вы короче
attacked us back then in the damn year Yes,
напали на нас тогда в чертом году Да
that's why our economy collapsed Yes, you
поэтому у нас экономика рухнула Да вы от
snatched part of our regions from us
нас оттяпали часть наших регионов
Yes, we
Да мы
maintained all this infrastructure and even
содержали всю эту инфраструктуру и даже
Despite the fact that we had a war going on that
Несмотря на то что у нас Шла война что
you attacked us, we  On January 1, 2022,
вы напали на нас мы к 1 января 2022 года
they reached the
вышли на показатели
minimum wage level indicators higher
минимального уровня оплаты труда выше
than in Russia by 30% And you already And this is not
чем в России на 30% Да и вы уже А это не
an indicator This is no yes So you have a mother, you
показатель Это нет да Так у тебя мама ты
say that no one gets there
говоришь что никто не получает там
because no one has reached such a level, you with
потому что никто на такой не вышел ты
your mouth  voiced that your mother
своим ртом озвучил что у тебя Мама
gets some thousand
получает там на какую-то там тысячу
more than the minimum
больше чем минимальный уровень оплаты
wage, so now our economy is
труда поэтому сейчас у нас да экономика
in the ass because you are on us  attacked and
в заднице потому что вы На нас напали и
we are all heading for war Yes, when will we
у нас всё идёт на войну Да когда мы
drive you out of our territory Yes,
выгоним вас с нашей территории Да
dismemberment of the city, what is it for, what is it for,
расчленинград чего це тоб для чего тоб
look at the axis Here is my face But for
там дивитись на ось Цей мий фейс Але для
you, it is one, two or three clicks But you,
тебе це один два або три клика Але ты
touch me and I will be KTA Wow  I have
тримае мене и я буду КТА Вау в мене там
a bunch of fouls there and I have a great mood
Купа фолов и в мене буде класний настрий
to do it but a cool video post on
щоб робити но крут вдео пись на й
Instagram for now Andriy that's
Instagram пок Андрий вот
it, let's
так давай я тебя
wait for you and
чекаю а